ALOY: So now that Talanah is a Hawk, she could become Sunhawk?
LIGAN: Yes, if she defeats Redmaw before Ahsis can, then she will take his place.
What exactly is Redmaw?
The meanest of all Thunderjaws, some say the first.
One swipe of its tail and five hunters go down.
It stomps can send boulders tumbling before it.
More than a few have been crushed under their weight.
And thus many have died trying to defeat it.
If Redmaw is so deadly, why do hunters keep going after it?
Anyone who defeats this beast will surely be considered a champion.
Who was Tarkas?
A respected hunter.
He sponsored Talanah many years ago.
If Talanah was his Thrush, why did he fight Redmaw without her?
I went to watch the battle.
She should have received word he'd picked up its trail.
Someone at the Lodge failed to pass it on.
Such skill from an outlander on your first attempt.
Take this Blazing Sun as your proof.
With so many Suns you may wish to speak to Aidaba in Meridian.
She will have special gear for you.
Right on target.
And up!
And go!
CARJA: Don't let your guard down…
CARJA: The Oseram guard will be blaming their shadows for their mistakes.
CARJA: Did she really save the Sun-King? A Nora?
CARJA: That crazy Oseram tried to kill our Sun-King,
but the machine rider stopped him cold.
CARJA: An Oseram tries to kill the Sun-King and a Nora saves his life.
I wouldn't believe it if I hadn't seen it with my own eyes.
CARJA: I bet those traitorous Oseram will conveniently
lose Dervahl in transport to Mainspring.
[Sun Priests singing]
So you've come back to the temple.
I was invited back.
The priests wanted to hear what I had to say
about reconciliation with the other tribes.
They're listening. At least, they've begun to listen.
There's a distance between ears and deeds.
Because of what we did?
What you did!
It was for the mourners, I think it helped them.
You set them on the path.
You can't know what their journeys hold.
Such is the priest's lot.
Perhaps a red robe would suit you.
[laugh] Not me.
Besides, your temple doesn't even take women.
We would be richer if we did.
Go in light, my friend, and let the Sun cast your way.
Thank you, Namman.
Where I'm going, I could probably use all the light I can get.
[Sun Priests singing]
VILGUND: Able bodied adventurers, preferably with no friends or family.
Outlander, are you looking for… wait, I know your face.
You came back! How did we fare?
Expensively.
That's what I was afraid of.
The tame machines…
It's hard to explain, but there was a kind of signal that calmed them.
Your men got greedy so it's gone now.
Gambling's a shoddy job, girl.
I should have been a weapons dealer, that's steady work.
Here, take it.
The half I'd owed those hammer-handed chunks.
Half? I finished the job.
And what was it you said?
"Enough to buy a more becoming garb."
What do you want, Carja silks?
Agh, hoisted on my own purse strings.
How are the trials going for you?
Have enough marks for a weapon yet?
I believe I have enough here. What next?
You brought in all the Sun marks at once!
You're going to make a lot of hunters jealous.
Not that it takes much.
I'm pleased to present to you a Lodge Blast Sling,
a Lodge Ropecaster, and the Lodge War Bow.
Congratulations! You're a Master Hunter of the Lodge.
All I can give you now is encouragement.
Where's Talanah? Maybe upstairs.
No Ahsis either.
Maybe Ligan knows where they are.
You have trophies?
I can hang on to them until the Sunhawk returns.
Where are Ahsis and Talanah?
Ahsis received word about Redmaw and rushed out.
Talanah found out a short time later and had to follow.
They both went alone?
Ahsis left without his Thrush, Talanah did as well.
Oh, I saw some outlanders follow after her.
I wouldn't put it past Ahsis to try something underhanded to get the kill.
Where have they gone? I have to help if I can.
Mmm, you might be right.
They've gone south-east, headed for the Spearshafts.
You'd better hurry.
MERCHANT: Only the finest goods here.
OSERAM: Here's to Avad, huh?
Now they're hunting me.
TALANAH: How much did Ahsis pay you?
ALOY: That sounds like her.
OUTLANDER: The Sun won't save you, get down!
ALOY: These must be the outlanders that followed Talanah. Looks—
ALOY: —like Ahsis hired some thugs.
OUTLANDER: May you die with–
OUTLANDER: The Sun's message to you!
Thank you.
I should have seen this coming.
Of course he would hire men to keep me from Redmaw.
They died for his pride.
Where is Ahsis now?
He's gone after Redmaw.
This way, hurry!
ALOY: Why is Ahsis going after Redmaw alone?
TALANAH: Vanity. He doesn't want to share credit for the kill with his Thrush.
TALANAH My sponsor did the same, went after Redmaw alone out of pride.
TALANAH: Even though he knew we needed to unseat Ahsis.
TALANAH: I'm not sure where Ahsis and Redmaw went from here.
ALOY: I can follow their tracks.
ALOY: This way, Redmaw destroyed these trees.
TALANAH: I fear we're too late.
TALANAH: With Tarkas I arrived in time to see him die from his wounds.
TALANAH: And with my father I didn't even get that.
ALOY: Where was Ahsis when your father passed?
TALANAH: Watching. He became Sunhawk that day.
TALANAH: But won't even speak of the event that made it possible.
TALANAH: That all changes today.
TALANAH: There he is!
ALOY: Ahsis is holding his own!
ALOY: Was. Was holding his own.
ALOY: Well, we have our work cut out for us.
ALOY: He saw me, this is it.
TALANAH: We've taken the wind out of him. He's half done!
TALANAH: We're doing it! He's nearly down, just a little bit more.
ALOY: Got him!
TALANAH: By the Sun, we did it!
TALANAH: Hello there, beautiful.
TALANAH: We make a great team.
ALOY: And now you're the Sunhawk.
TALANAH: About that…
Talanah, he's still alive.
Out of the way Nora filth.
You're done. The Lodge is finally free of your influence.
I kept it alive in dark times.
No, you buried it along with my father's memory.
AHSIS: I should have …
I should have let you fight Redmaw first to soften him up.
Damn.
Here lies the Sunhawk of the Hunters Lodge.
It's almost a shame.
After all that you're gonna weep for him?
Oh, no.
I just wish I could've seen his face when I succeeded him.
Okay, then.
Meet me back at the Hunters Lodge, if you have the time.
I have a feeling the new Sunhawk wants to welcome you.
My Focus is receiving another signal.
That Tallneck can't be far now.
Okay, I need to get up to the Tallneck's head.
Calm, calm.
Back to your business.
Couldn't let you call for help.
That hurt it!
This should be a good spot for jumping onto the Tallneck.
Okay, time to climb up to its head.
Alright, got what I need.
[whistle]
Never know when I might need these.
Nil, I did wonder on my way here, well, if you were luring me into an ambush.
Where's the fun in that?
Some bandit sprawl would never have done for our arena.
But this? Much better. There's a sense of drama.
So, what do you say?
How about we try to kill each other?
You brought me out here to ask if I want to fight you?
To the death. We'll savour it because we only get this one time.
Actually, I don't know what else I expected.
You are so conscientious,
I wouldn't want to push you into something that wasn't genuine.
Especially death, there is nothing more genuine.
I'm, umm, flattered that you think of me this way.
But I don't want to kill you.
Don't be hasty.
When it's life against death, hunter against hunter, I know it'll come to you.
Is that really what you want, Nil?
You know, I don't think you have a death wish.
What you have might be worse,
but I see there might be a need for you in this world.
I don't understand.
I won't fight you, that's my decision.
You can respect it or try to shoot me in the back as I go.
Then it's over. Your last arrow is the cruellest.
Umm…
It's true, I offered you the choice, but my heart is broken.